<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nick Chandler</title>
    <link>https://nickchandler.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nick Chandler</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 09:09:15 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nickchandler.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>wishr Repo Setup</title>
      <link>https://nickchandler.dev/articles/2023/11/29/wishr-repo-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 09:09:15 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nickchandler.dev/articles/2023/11/29/wishr-repo-setup/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, I described why I&amp;rsquo;m writing a small Unix shell, which I&amp;rsquo;m calling wishr, along with a bit of an overview of how I plan to approach the project. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to get started on the shell, itself, but it&amp;rsquo;s important to get a new repo set up for success. So, in this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll go through the initial repository setup I&amp;rsquo;ve gone with.
If you&amp;rsquo;d like to look at the specific git commit, here it is!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>wishr - A Small Shell Written in Rust</title>
      <link>https://nickchandler.dev/articles/2023/11/25/wishr-a-small-shell-written-in-rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 22:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nickchandler.dev/articles/2023/11/25/wishr-a-small-shell-written-in-rust/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post in a series where I plan to document my experience writing a small Unix shell in Rust called wishr. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll describe why I&amp;rsquo;m starting this project and how I plan to proceed through it.
Why write a shell? Link to heading First off, to be clear, I have no intention to make a production quality shell: Bash, Z Shell, fish, and the like, can all breathe a sigh of relief here!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://nickchandler.dev/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 17:10:36 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nickchandler.dev/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! &amp;#x1f44b;
My name is Nick, and I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineer in Indiana (in the United States). I focus on backend, behind-the-scenes, software; if I am making a UI, it is probably a CLI. &amp;#x1f604;
I enjoy learning about computer systems and software, and on this site, I hope to post occasionally about interesting things I learn as well as personal projects I work on.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
