<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Nick Chandler</title>
    <link>https://nickchandler.dev/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Nick Chandler</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 23:30:34 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nickchandler.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Faster Software Development with the Mikado Method</title>
      <link>https://nickchandler.dev/articles/2024/09/21/faster-software-development-with-the-mikado-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:37:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nickchandler.dev/articles/2024/09/21/faster-software-development-with-the-mikado-method/</guid>
      <description>As a software engineer, have you ever faced a complex project where every task seems to depend on another? My team at HashiCorp ran into just that — and found a method that helped us tackle those interdependencies in a way that lets us make smooth progress. Here’s how the Mikado Method improved our workflow.&#xA;The Challenge Link to heading About a year ago, my team at HashiCorp tried something new.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>wishr Repo Setup</title>
      <link>https://nickchandler.dev/articles/2023/11/29/wishr-repo-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 09:09:15 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nickchandler.dev/articles/2023/11/29/wishr-repo-setup/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, I described why I&amp;rsquo;m writing a small Unix shell, which I&amp;rsquo;m calling wishr, along with a bit of an overview of how I plan to approach the project. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to get started on the shell, itself, but it&amp;rsquo;s important to get a new repo set up for success. So, in this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll go through the initial repository setup I&amp;rsquo;ve gone with.&#xA;If you&amp;rsquo;d like to look at the specific git commit, here it is!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>wishr - A Small Shell Written in Rust</title>
      <link>https://nickchandler.dev/articles/2023/11/25/wishr-a-small-shell-written-in-rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 22:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nickchandler.dev/articles/2023/11/25/wishr-a-small-shell-written-in-rust/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post in a series where I plan to document my experience writing a small Unix shell in Rust called wishr. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll describe why I&amp;rsquo;m starting this project and how I plan to proceed through it.&#xA;Why write a shell? Link to heading First off, to be clear, I have no intention to make a production quality shell: Bash, Z Shell, fish, and the like, can all breathe a sigh of relief here!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
